<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Devops on</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in Devops on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 10:51:54 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gosang.github.io/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting Up and Running Elastic Kibana Locally using Docker and Docker Desktop</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/devops/setting-up-and-running-elastic-kibana-locally-using-docker-and-docker-desktop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 10:51:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/devops/setting-up-and-running-elastic-kibana-locally-using-docker-and-docker-desktop/</guid><description>In this technical blog, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to set up and run Elastic Kibana locally using Docker and Docker Desktop on Windows 11. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover what Elastic Kibana is, its benefits, and step-by-step instructions for basic installation and configuration.
What is Elastic Kibana? Elastic Kibana is an open-source data visualization tool designed to work with Elasticsearch. It provides a user-friendly interface for exploring, analyzing, and visualizing data stored in Elasticsearch indexes.</description></item><item><title>Docker 101: Creating Database Container</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/devops/docker/docker-101-creating-database-container/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 12:10:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/devops/docker/docker-101-creating-database-container/</guid><description>In this blog, we&amp;rsquo;ll look into the world of Docker and explore how to create database containers using Docker and Docker Compose. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover the rationale behind Docker, its benefits, and how it resolves common problems in software development. Additionally, we&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to set up a popular database, PostgreSQL using Docker and Docker Compose.
What is Docker? Docker is a platform that enables developers to package applications and their dependencies into lightweight, portable containers.</description></item><item><title>Modern Devops Branching Strategies: a Guide to Efficient Development Workflows</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/devops/modern-devops-branching-strategies-a-guide-to-efficient-development-workflows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 20:03:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/devops/modern-devops-branching-strategies-a-guide-to-efficient-development-workflows/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced software development world, DevOps has emerged as a vital approach for fostering collaboration between development and operations teams. A key component of DevOps is the use of branching strategies, which help teams manage code effectively, streamline workflows, and boost development efficiency.
In this blog, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore modern DevOps branching strategies, starting with the importance and rationale behind these strategies. We&amp;rsquo;ll then discuss key considerations for selecting a branching strategy and look into the most common approaches, including GitFlow, GitHub Flow, GitLab Flow, and Trunk-Based Development (TBD), along with their specific use cases, pros, cons, and their integration with CI/CD pipelines.</description></item></channel></rss>