<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Design Principles on</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/series/design-principles/</link><description>Recent content in Design Principles on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 08:43:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gosang.github.io/series/design-principles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Feature Flags</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-principles/feature-flags/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 08:43:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-principles/feature-flags/</guid><description>In the fast-paced world of software development, adapting to changing requirements and user needs is crucial. Feature Flags or Feature Toggles, emerge as a powerful technique to enable or disable features in a system without changing code. This blog explores what Feature Flags are, their rationale, advantages over conventional approaches, and practical implementation in a .NET 6 e-commerce system.
What are Feature Flags? Feature Flags are a development technique that allows developers to flag/toggle features in a system on or off at runtime without modifying code.</description></item><item><title>SOLID Design Principles</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-principles/solid/solid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 13:13:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-principles/solid/solid/</guid><description>SOLID is a set of five design principles that aim to create robust, scalable, and maintainable software. These principles were introduced by Robert C. Martin and have become a cornerstone for object-oriented design. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into each SOLID principle, discuss their rationale, provide practical examples in C# .NET Core, and explore how they can be applied in both monolithic and microservices architectures.
What is SOLID? SOLID is an acronym that represents five design principles:</description></item><item><title>DRY Design Principle</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-principles/dry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 13:26:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-principles/dry/</guid><description>In the realm of software development, the Don&amp;rsquo;t-Repeat-Yourself (DRY) design principle stands as a cornerstone, emphasizing the importance of avoiding redundancy in code. This principle is more than just a catchy phrase; it&amp;rsquo;s a philosophy that guides developers toward writing efficient, maintainable, and scalable code. In this blog, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into the essence of DRY, its rationale, its application in microservices and modular monolithic architectures, and its practical implementation in an e-commerce system using C# dot net core examples.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Idempotency in Microservices with .NET Core</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-principles/microservices/idempotency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 13:58:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-principles/microservices/idempotency/</guid><description>Introduction In distributed systems and microservices architecture, ensuring the reliability and consistency of operations becomes a critical challenge. One key concept that plays a pivotal role in addressing this challenge is Idempotency. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into the meaning of Idempotency, explore its rationale, understand its applications in the context of microservices (using .NET Core), and discuss the advantages, disadvantages, and best practices associated with it.
What is Idempotency?</description></item></channel></rss>