<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Next.js on</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/tags/next.js/</link><description>Recent content in Next.js on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 12:44:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gosang.github.io/tags/next.js/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implementing Cookie-Based Stateless Sessions in Next.js Using Server Actions</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/react/implementing-cookie-based-stateless-sessions-in-next-js-using-server-actions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 12:44:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/react/implementing-cookie-based-stateless-sessions-in-next-js-using-server-actions/</guid><description>Introduction In modern web development, managing user sessions efficiently and securely is crucial. One approach is to use cookie-based stateless sessions. This method leverages cookies to store session data client-side, reducing server-side complexity and improving scalability. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to implement cookie-based stateless sessions in a Next.js application using Server Actions, focusing on managing user settings like theme preferences.
What is Cookie-Based Stateless Session? A cookie-based stateless session involves storing session data in cookies, allowing the server to remain stateless.</description></item><item><title>Simplifying the Next.js Server Actions</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/react/simplifying-the-nextjs-server-actions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 11:40:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/react/simplifying-the-nextjs-server-actions/</guid><description>Next.js continues to revolutionize the web development landscape with its powerful features and seamless integration with modern tools. One such feature is Server Actions, a unique offering that sets Next.js apart from traditional React applications. This blog post will look into Next.js Server Actions, exploring what they are, their rationale, key concepts, and functions. We&amp;rsquo;ll also highlight the differences between Next.js and React, and between server and client actions. Additionally, we&amp;rsquo;ll provide a sample Next.</description></item></channel></rss>