<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MongoDB on</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/tags/mongodb/</link><description>Recent content in MongoDB on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 18:01:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gosang.github.io/tags/mongodb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implementing Mongodb Atlas With ASP.NET Core Using CQRS</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/datastore/implementing-mongodb-atlas-with-dotnet-core-using-cqrs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 18:01:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/datastore/implementing-mongodb-atlas-with-dotnet-core-using-cqrs/</guid><description>Introduction In modern application development, choosing the right database solution is crucial for building scalable and efficient systems. MongoDB Atlas, combined with ASP.NET Core and the CQRS (Command Query Responsibility Segregation) pattern, offers a powerful and flexible solution for developing microservices-based applications. This technical blog aims to guide you through the process of implementing MongoDB Atlas with ASP.NET Core using the CQRS pattern, covering key aspects such as MediatR, Docker, and best practices.</description></item><item><title>Mongodb Atlas With .NET Core</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/datastore/mongodb-atlas-with-dotnet-core/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 18:01:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/datastore/mongodb-atlas-with-dotnet-core/</guid><description>Introduction In modern web development, choosing the right database solution is pivotal to building scalable and robust applications. MongoDB Atlas, coupled with ASP.NET Core, offers a compelling combination for developers seeking flexibility, scalability, and ease of development. This technical blog aims to provide a comprehensive understanding of MongoDB Atlas, its integration with ASP.NET Core, and the best practices for building microservices in the context of an e-commerce system.
MongoDB Atlas: Unveiling the Power What is MongoDB Atlas?</description></item></channel></rss>