<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Caching on</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/series/caching/</link><description>Recent content in Caching on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 08:43:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gosang.github.io/series/caching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implementing Redis as a Cache Service in .NET Core</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-patterns/caching/implementing-redis-cache-in-dotnet-core/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 08:43:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-patterns/caching/implementing-redis-cache-in-dotnet-core/</guid><description>Caching is a critical component in modern software development, playing a crucial role in optimizing performance, reducing latency, and enhancing overall user experience. In the context of microservices or modular monolithic applications, implementing Redis as a Cache Service is a powerful strategy. In this blog post, we will explore what Redis is, the rationale behind using it as a Cache Service, its implementation in an e-commerce system using .NET Core, and best practices.</description></item><item><title>Difference Between Imemorycache and Redis</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-patterns/caching/difference-between-imemorycache-and-redis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 08:43:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-patterns/caching/difference-between-imemorycache-and-redis/</guid><description>Caching is a pivotal technique in optimizing application performance, and in the world of .NET Core, developers have two powerful tools at their disposal: .NET Core IMemoryCache and Redis Caching. Each solution has distinct characteristics and is tailored for specific use cases.
.NET Core IMemoryCache Overview: In .NET Core, the IMemoryCache interface is a built-in caching mechanism that provides an in-memory store for frequently accessed data. It is part of the Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>Caching Pattern</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-patterns/caching/caching-pattern/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 08:43:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/design-patterns/caching/caching-pattern/</guid><description>Caching is a crucial aspect of modern software development, especially in the context of microservices or modular monolithic applications. It helps improve performance, reduce latency, and enhance the overall user experience. In this blog post, we will delve into five caching patterns: Cache Aside, Write Through, Read Through, Write Back, and Write Around, exploring their characteristics, use cases, and code snippets using .NET.
1. Cache Aside Overview: Cache Aside, also known as Lazy Loading, is a popular caching pattern where the application code is responsible for managing the cache.</description></item></channel></rss>