<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>JavaScript on</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/tags/javascript/</link><description>Recent content in JavaScript on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 20:34:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gosang.github.io/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>JavaScript Security Risks and Best Practices for Mitigation</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/react/javascript-security-risks-and-best-practices-for-mitigation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 20:34:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/react/javascript-security-risks-and-best-practices-for-mitigation/</guid><description>JavaScript is one of the most popular programming languages for web development. It powers dynamic content on web pages, enabling interactive and responsive user experiences. However, its ubiquity and powerful features also make it a target for various security threats. Understanding the security risks associated with JavaScript and implementing best practices to mitigate them is essential for developers and businesses alike.
In this blog, we will explore common JavaScript security risks, provide code examples to illustrate these risks, and discuss best practices for secure coding.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Memory Leaks in JavaScript and How to Prevent Them</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/react/understanding-memory-leaks-in-javascript-and-how-to-prevent-them/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 20:34:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/react/understanding-memory-leaks-in-javascript-and-how-to-prevent-them/</guid><description>Memory management is crucial in software development, even in a language like JavaScript, which features automatic garbage collection. Memory leaks occur when memory that is no longer needed is not released, leading to performance issues over time. In this blog, we will look into memory leaks in JavaScript, their causes, and prevention techniques, with clear examples and best practices.
What Are Memory Leaks in JavaScript? A memory leak happens when a program unintentionally retains memory that it no longer needs, causing the application to consume more memory than required.</description></item><item><title>Callback Promise Async Await in Javascript</title><link>https://gosang.github.io/posts/react/callback-promise-async-await-in-javascript/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 20:34:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gosang.github.io/posts/react/callback-promise-async-await-in-javascript/</guid><description>JavaScript is a single-threaded language, which means it executes one operation at a time. But real-world applications often need to handle multiple tasks, like fetching data, reading files, or waiting for user input. To manage these asynchronous operations, JavaScript provides Callbacks, Promises, and Async/Await. This blog explores these tools in depth, covering their rationale, usage, advantages, and challenges.
1. Callback A Callback is a function passed as an argument to another function and executed after the completion of that function.</description></item></channel></rss>